<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[@jairobjunior - Mobile Life]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.jairobjunior.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.jairobjunior.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-25T17:34:32-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.jairobjunior.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jairo Barros Junior]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secrets to working remotely]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.jairobjunior.com/blog/blog/2014/01/24/secrets-to-working-remotely/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-24T21:02:34-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.jairobjunior.com/blog/blog/2014/01/24/secrets-to-working-remotely</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past 10 years I have worked as a software architect both in an office structure and as a freelancer. For the last year and a half, I have made a full transition into working remotely. If you are in the tech business, chances are you do work from home anyways. So why not have the freedom to live anywhere in the world?</p>

<p>Here are tips to keeping your clients happy and maximizing the success of your business.</p>

<h3>Be available</h3>

<p>Just because you are not in an office together doesn&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t still form the same sense of connection. I like Skype as a way of touching base through out the day. Set your status to &ldquo;online&rdquo; on both your computer and your phone. Even if your client or co workers don&rsquo;t need to talk to you, just knowing you are easily accessible will create a security for you both.
I&rsquo;ve tested this principle unintentionally&hellip;</p>

<h3>Answer emails quickly</h3>

<p>If you are prospecting new clients and</p>

<h3>Invoice</h3>

<h3>Pay Pal</h3>

<h3>Don&rsquo;t let tension go unspoken</h3>

<p>As a remote worker, you are an easy target for being blamed if anything goes wrong with the project. Don&rsquo;t let this get to you, just try to keep clear communication with your client. For example, if a project is late, it is easy to blame the fact that you are not in the office. However</p>

<h3>Keep your Linkedin updated</h3>

<h3>Hire an assistant</h3>

<h3>How to save money</h3>

<ul>
<li>Live below your budget</li>
<li>Ask yourself if it is an investment</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
